Piotr Sieminski

Data/Analytics Engineering with DBT, Airflow, AWS and Snowflake. International experience in many sector and size companies. In my spare time I love to do horseback archery as well as learning new languages.

+48 514 363 122 piotr.sieminski@data-service s.dev

EXPERIENCE

Swiss Marketplace Group, Zurich (Remote contract) — *Data Engineer*

February 2023 - PRESENT

- Stack: AWS, Astronomer, Docker, Kubernetes, SQL, Python, ETL, DBT, Snowflake, Airflow, YAML, Atlan
- Executed full migration from Matillion ETL tool into dbt-core deployed with managed airflow on Astronomer Cloud
- Assumed DevOps tasks for CI/CD pipeline and organisation of the tes/prod branches in GitHub

Preply, Barcelona (Remote contract) — *Sr. Data/Analytics Engineer*

January 2023 - February 2023

- Stack: SQL, Python, ETL, DBT, Snowflake, Airflow, Monte Carlo, YAML, Atlan
- Built from scratch and deployed 'Blueprint' automated marketing tool for building out Google keywords and uploading them to Google Ads
- Migrated the old ETL infrastructure into DBT
- Leading the project team of Analytics Engineers and Data Scientists building E2E marketing reporting and attribution pipelines
- Enhanced and introduced several governance processes and monitoring resulting in a 57% decrease in data incidents over the past 3 months

Dojo, London — Senior/Lead Analytics Engineer

November 2021 - December 2022

- Stack: SQL, Python, ETL, DBT, GCP, Airflow, Monte Carlo, YAML
- Modelled 100+ tables following staging, transform, prod best practices, as a result built whole reporting for one of the Tribes
- Monitoring of data pipelines and designing DWH architecture
- Delivered Looker training for the Tribe
- Automated customer personas data product to classify

SKILLS

- ★ SQL
- ★ DBT, Airflow
- ★ Snowflake, AWS
- **★** Monte Carlo
- ★ GitHub, CI/CD
- ★ Atlan (Data Catalogue)
- **★** YAML
- ★ Looker, Tableau
- ★ ETL/ELT
- ★ Leadership/mentorsh ip
- ★ Python 3
- ★ Stakeholders management
- **★** Communication
- **★** Constructive feedback

PORTFOLIO

- □ GitLab
- □ VS Code SOL

 Performance

 Optimiser Extension

 (marketplace)
- <u>Data Engineering</u>
 <u>pipeline</u> (astro-cli,
 airflow, dbt, postgres,
 docker)

- (KMeans) customers and pull their characteristics to enable Product decisions
- Defined KPIs for squads and Tribe, built KPI Trees
- Defined new standardised processes for pilots, event tracking specs
- Led the the Analytics Team for Payments Tribe
- Introduced implicit metric for CSAT for terminal payments
- Created App Insights Data Product for all Dojo customers
- Coaching less experienced analysts

Quandoo, **Berlin/London** — Business Intelligence

January 2021 - October 2021

- Stack: SQL, Python, ETL, DBT, GCP, Airflow
- DBT table modelling
- Initialised and delivered implementation of a new feature, which increased transactions volume; annual projected increase in revenue of ~EUR 146k
- Reduced BigQuery costs by ~13% thanks to Tableau Dashboards management and custom, optimised scheduled queries management
- I linked together Google Search Console and our internal data for SEO Dashboard project, that allows marketing teams to track pages performance from one place, all together

Booking.com, Amsterdam— Junior Safety Analyst

January 2019 - January 2021

- Stack: SQL, Python, ETL, Hadoop
- Introduced version controls to the security teams for SQL Code
- Automated many small processes saving operational teams
 1h/day in total of manual work
- Delivered on migration to the new task management tool (Swimlane) which allowed operational teams to increase productivity by ~60%; savings are estimated ~EUR 450k per annum
- Improved over 20 customer service procedures/processes, which decreased Average Handling Time by ~30%
- Prepared reporting dashboards directly for the board of directors
- Completed mentorship with a Data Scientist

EDUCATION

University of Essex, *Data Science - Master's degree*May 2022 - May 2024

Polish-Japanese Academy of Information Technology, Computer Science - Engineer's degree

January 2019 - January 2021 (no graduation - used as a basis to move on straight to the Master's degree in the UK)

CERTIFICATES

- AWS: Certified Developer
- Dbt Labs: Certified dbt Developer
- Snowflake: SnowPro Core

Hobbies

- Horseback archery
- Used to be a professional swimmer
- Learning new languages